discovertuscany.com 2019-07-17

# Discover Tuscany - Legal Notes about Copyright, Privacy and Cookie Policy and Disclaimers

## Copyright

All content of the sites, including text, photographs and graphics are property of WebPromoter, except photographic content provided by service providers that that have provided us explicit consent to promote their services. All content on the site is protected by Italian and European copyright law, **no content can be copied, imitated or used even in part unless consent is requested and granted in writing by Webpromoter**.

## FTC Disclosure

DiscoverTuscany.com participates in press trips and blog tours and occasionally receives free products or services, such as books and free admittance into events. It also receives payment for reviews of accommodations or services tied to the tourism sector, such as tours, cooking classes or wedding planning, to name a few. All reviews resulting from a paid sponsorship, free gift, blog trip or direct experience express the personal and honest opinion of the author and are explicitly indicated as such in the article itself. In particular, all reviews resulting from a paid sponsorship will be indicated as “sponsored article”.

## Disclaimer

Our DiscoverTuscany.com team strives to provide high quality, up to date and correct content, but it is still possible that you might find errors within our pages. DiscoverTuscany.com and WebPromoter Snc accept no responsibility for the consequences of decisions made based on errors found on this website. 

### Affiliate Links

DiscoverTuscany.com / WebPromoter Snc participates in affiliate marketing programs including Booking.com, New Globus Viaggi, Viator Inc, Rentalcars.com, Parclick and FlixBus. Any links to those sites may earn advertising fees and are indicated as such where they appear. By buying through our affiliates, we earn a monetary commission and thus you support our website and keep all the info we offer on here free.

### Ads by Google

The **Ads by Google** are provided through the Google Adsense program, and should show interesting ads based on your interests and searches. Clicks on these ads also contribute to supporting our website as we earn a commission on each click.

## Italian newspaper disclaimer

"Questo sito non rappresenta una testata giornalistica poichè viene aggiornato occasionalmente e senza alcuna periodicità. Pertanto, non può essere considerato in alcun modo un prodotto editoriale ai sensi della Legge n. 62 del 07.03.2001."

## Privacy Policy

### Introduction: the GDPR and privacy

The General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) is a European Commission Regulation ( _EU 2016/679)_ with which the European Union strengthens and standardizes the protection of private personal data of citizens and residents of the European Union, both within and outside its borders. This regulation replaces the laws of the individual Member States in terms of privacy and enters into force May 25, 2018.

For more details, you read the [official text of the GDPR](https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/HTML/?uri=CELEX:32016R0679&from=IT), visit Italy’s [Data Protection Authority](http://www.garanteprivacy.it/web/guest/home_en) website and and the page on [Wikipedia](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/General_Data_Protection_Regulation).

In accordance to the GDPR, this privacy statement serves to clearly and simply explain which personal data is collected through this site, where it is stored, for how long, with what purpose and how you can update it or request it deletion.

### Who is the data controller: WebPromoter

**_DiscoverTuscany.com_** belongs to Webpromoter S.n.c. di S. Romeo & C. VAT# IT05515250487 to which we refer to later as “WebPromoter”.

WebPromoter is a private company based in Florence, with offices in via G.b. Vico 32 (Italy).

WebPromoter manages the site listed above and controls the management of personal data as described in this statement, in accordance with the current privacy laws ( _General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) - EU Regulation 2016/679_ ).

You can contact us by email at webpromoter@registerpec.it (PEC) or info@discovertuscany.com.

### On what legal basis does WebPromoter collect and manage personal data?

WebPromoter uses as a legal basis the need to process personal data for the execution of its services, which include responding for requests for information on Tuscany, accommodation recommendations, itinerary help and general information on visiting the region. Without collecting the requested data on forms, it would not be possible for us to respond to the requests of the site user.

Webpromoter relies on its legitimate commercial interest to provide its services, promote them, prevent fraud and spam and improve its services.

Where required by applicable law, we ask for your consent before processing your personal data for direct marketing purposes.

### What type of data does WebPromoter collect on DiscoverTuscany.com?

WebPromoter collects the information you send us through the contact forms on this site.

**For users** who request information, such data includes your name, email, website and telephone number, in addition to any other information you choose to add to your request.

The same form is used by anyone **interested in promoting their services on our sites** so the requested information is the same.

For each form sent, we collect data related to the browser and operating system used and the IP address, both of which serve to fight spam and to identify any usability problems on our sites in relation to particular browser settings and devices.

When you visit our site, we also automatically collect information related to your visit. Your IP address, the date and time of access to our site, hardware, software or browser you use and information about your computer's operating system and language settings is recorded. We also collect information about your clicks and the pages you've viewed on our sites, as well as information that tells us which sites or marketing campaigns you used to visit our sites.

### Why does WebPromoter collect this data on DiscoverTuscany.com?

The data you send us through the form on our site are first of all used to provide the information you request.

Data sent through the form is collected to provide, through email or by phone, additional information and personalized offers for advertising on our sites. Only in the case of explicit consent would we use the data to send additional offers related to our sites aimed solely at service providers in Tuscany.

WebPromoter keeps a copy of requests in its archives for statistical purposes and as a backup.

WebPromoter sends an email confirming that the request has been correctly sent and this email may include additional information, including links to articles or offers on WebPromoter sites or partner sites. Only in the case of explicit consent would WebPromoter send further communications via email containing information and offers of interest for those planning a visit to Tuscany.

Finally, the data sent through compiled forms can be used to show you personalized online advertising campaigns (remarketing) rather than generic advertisements, through specialized platforms such as Google Adwords and Facebook Advertising. In this case, users of the sites are grouped into virtual lists, in aggregate form not traceable to individual users, based on the location of the accommodation facility (in the case of facility managers) or on the dates of planned stays, on the site and pages visited and the actions performed (such as sending a request or subscription to the newsletter). This information is to provide advertisements targeted to your interests rather than generic ads through advertising platforms such as Google and Facebook.

### Where is the collected data stored and for how long?

The data collected through our forms and browsing of our sites is collected through the following platforms:

  * [Google Analytics](https://analytics.google.com/) \- data related to site navigation.
  * [Google Gmail](https://www.google.com/gmail/) \- each completed form generates an email sent to WebPromoter, stored on Google’s Gmail servers ([Google Suite](https://gsuite.google.com/)).
  * Google Docs - data can be exported to documents stored in again on Google servers, through the [Google Suite](https://gsuite.google.com/) services.
  * [Mailchimp ](https://mailchimp.com/)\- registration to our newsletters is handled directly through Mailchimp forms.
  * On databases stored on our hosting servers provided by [Pair.com](https://www.pair.com/)
  * On documents and databases stored locally in our WebPromoter office in Florence, Italy.
  * On documents and databases stored on cloud services provided by [Amazon AWS](https://aws.amazon.com/)

The transmission of personal data as described in this Privacy Policy may include the transfer overseas to countries that do not provide complete and comprehensive data protection laws such as those of European Union countries. Where required by Community law, we will only transfer personal data to recipients that offer an adequate level of protection of personal data. Google, Amazon, Facebook and Mailchimp are leading international companies and their servers are spread out all over the world, including outside EU countries. Pair.com has its own servers in Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, USA. WebPromoter is based in Florence, Italy.

WebPromoter relies on specific procedures to prevent improper use and unauthorized access to data. Only authorized personnel can access personal data to carry out their work. We keep your personal data for as long as deemed necessary to enable you to use our services, perform our services, advertise our services, carry out our business activities, to comply with legal obligations and resolve any disputes. All personal data stored by us is protected by this Privacy Policy. If you have questions regarding a specific data retention period for certain types of personal data we process, please contact us as indicated below.

### Which third parties does WebPromoter share your data with?

The data collected through forms is sent through email to WebPromoter, which manages DiscoverTuscany.com. Your data is not share with any other third party.

Data relating to browsing history and use of our sites is collected through tools such as Google Analytics and shared only in aggregate form (not attributable to individual users) with WebPromoter, its collaborators and partners.

We share only some personal data, such as your e-mail address, with advertising partners for the sole purpose of advertising DiscoverTuscany.com (to ensure that the most appropriate users receive relevant and targeted ads). We share e-mail addresses only in an encrypted format so that they can be matched to existing customer databases.

### How does WebPromoter treat personal data of minors?

Services offered by WebPromoter are only for users over the age of 16. Any user under the age of 16 can use our services only with explicit parental consent (or that of a legal guardian). If we learn we have personal data for someone under 16 years of age without the valid consent of a parent or legal guardian, we reserve the right to delete such data.

### How to check, update and possibly delete the personal data you have shared with Webpromoter?

In accordance with current privacy laws ( _General Data Protection Regulation (GDRP) - EU Regulation 2016/679_ ) and upon request, you have the right to review the personal data WebPromoter keeps about you. You can send us an email at info@discovertuscany.com or webpromoter@registerpec.it where you can ask us for a copy of the personal data we hold about you, inform us of any changes or corrections you want made or ask us to permanently delete or restrict the processing of the personal data we have about you from our archives.

Every communication we send through the Mailchimp platform also provides a link to update or unsubscribe from any future mailings. We will always do our best to respond promptly and exhaustively to each request as is our duty. The user always has the right to file a complaint with the supervisory authority.

In order to learn of updates or changes to the current policies, upon further changes in laws, it is best if users consult this page periodically.

* * *

## Terms and Conditions

### Bookings with recommended services and other third party resellers

**WebPromoter Snc is not a travel agency and is not involved in the management of bookings of accommodation, museum tickets, bus tickets, guided tours or car rentals.** Webpromoter reviews these types of services to provide a useful start for users interested in planning their vacations in Tuscany, offering links to official websites and affiliated partners to facilitate such bookings. In this manner, users plan independently their itineraries and book directly with the third party for services they are interested in, with no intervention/involvement by WebPromoter.

### Website content and Review Criteria

WebPromoter is not responsible for the content of any external sites not belonging to WebPromoter.

WebPromoter writes its own reviews of accommodations and other services it has experienced in first person, often times also using information found on official websites and other external websites. WebPromoter is not responsible if such information is found to not correspond to the truth or is not updated. The user is invited to always check the information through other sources on the Web. Our reviews are based on subjective editorial criteria established by WebPromoter.

* * *

## Cookie Policy

This website uses cookies. In this statement we explain in detail which cookies we use and how these allow us to offer our users the best online experience possible.

By using our site, the user accepts the use of cookies as explained below.

### What is a cookie?

A cookie is a brief text file sent by the website you have visited to your browser, either on your computer or mobile device. A cookie allows our website to receive feedback on your site activity, such as your default language and other settings. This allows us to offer a better experience during your visit and make successive visits to our site easier, increasing the utility of the website in your favor. Cookies play an important role on the Web. Without them, navigating the Web would be a more frustrating experience.

There are various types of cookies and ways of using them. Cookies can be distinguished by the function they play, their duration and by the entity that adds them to a website.

#### How are cookies used?

Our website uses the following types of cookies:

  * ### Technical/functional cookies

Some cookies are indispensable for the correct operation of our website since they allow the loading of the web page and the correct operation of all of the essential functional aspects of the website. Other technical cookies add functions and help or personalize the overall experience of your browsing activity on our website.

  * ### Analytics cookies (by third-parties)

These are cookies that allow us to monitor and analyze the behavior of all users of our sites. Through these cookies, we are able to monitor how navigation occurs within the website and we can create profiles of the types of users on our site in order to make improvements based on the analysis of this data. These cookies (offered by third parties) give us _anonymous/aggregate data_ on site activity which means we cannot identify any single user.

In particular, Google Analytics, an analytics system offered by Google Inc., uses cookies saved on your computer to make it possible to analyze how you navigate through a website. The information generated by these cookies on the use and navigation of a site are sent to Google’s servers in the United States. Google uses this information to monitor and examine how each user goes in and around a website, creating reports on the activity on the website and to offer services tied to the activity of the website. Users who don’t want these types of cookies on their computer can actually opt-out from having them saved on their computers by installing the plug-in “Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on” offered by Google here:[ https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout). To activate this add-on, which blocks your computer from sending any information about your visit to Google, you have to follow instructions on the page, then restart your browser.

Read this page to learn how to refuse or delete cookies installed by Google:[ http://www.google.com/intl/en/privacypolicy.html](http://www.google.com/intl/en/privacypolicy.html)

Read this page to read Google’s privacy policy:[ http://www.google.co.uk/intl/en/policies/privacy/](http://www.google.co.uk/intl/en/policies/privacy/)

  * ### Profiling cookies (by third-parties)

We use various providers on our website that can install cookies directly to make sure their services work correctly. If you wish to have more information on which ones are present and how to disable/uninstall them, keep reading and follow the links in this section.

In addition, by going to[ http://www.youronlinechoices.com/](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/), you can find information about how behavioral advertising works and have the possibility of turning on or off specific companies among the list of providers listed who work with website providers to collect and use information to provide online behavioral advertising.

These cookies memorize the information based on browsing activity to deliver advertising that reflects these interests.

We also utilize **Google Adwords** tools and remarketing lists for ads in the Display network of Google Adwords. We use cookies installed by Google (separate ones for Google Analytics and Google Adwords) and other third-party cookies (including ones by DoubleClick) combined together to inform, optimize and publish ads based on previous visits to our website. This means that providers (such as Google) then publish our promotional material on other websites that the user visits across the Web.

Some of our cookies work to create a user profile while others offer anonymous statistical data on browsing activity on our website; this function can be disabled through your browser.

These cookies (third-party advertising services) are used to publish personalized ads and content based on browsing activity on our site. Below you can find the privacy pages for each service and the opt-out option where it is possible to disable the use of third-party profiling cookies.

#### Google

  * Adwords: Remarketing and Conversion Campaigns

  * Remarketing and Conversion Cookies

  * Doubleclick

  * Privacy Policy - <https://www.google.com/intl/it/policies/technologies/ads/>

  * Opt-out option - <https://www.google.com/settings/u/0/ads>

#### Addthis

  * Privacy policy - <http://www.addthis.com/privacy>
  * Opt-out option - <http://www.addthis.com/privacy/opt-out>

  * ### Social Media Cookies

These third-party cookies are used to integrate various tools used by main social media platforms within the website. In particular, they permit you to register and login on our site with your own Facebook account (on our Forum).

#### Facebook

Privacy policy:[ https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/](https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/)

Facebook offers sponsored ads based on your own browsing activity on Facebook as well as interests. For further details:[ https://www.facebook.com/help/cookies?ref_type=sitefooter](https://www.facebook.com/help/cookies?ref_type=sitefooter)

  * ### Web beacons

We use Web beacons; these elements are images found on a page or email whose function is to monitor the online activity of users that visit our site or that receive our newsletter.

The objective of using this technology is to monitor user activity, identifying the pages visited within the site and time spent browsing/reading.

### How to disable cookies on your browser

All of the main web browsers are initially set up to accept cookies automatically. The user can modify these settings to block cookies or to receive an alert message when cookies are sent to your device. There are various ways to manage cookies.

The user should refer to manuals or Help sections of their browser to learn how to regulate or change their browser settings.

  * Chrome:[ https://support.google.com/accounts/answer/61416?hl=it](https://support.google.com/accounts/answer/61416?hl=it)

  * Firefox:[ https://support.mozilla.org/it/kb/Attivare%20e%20disattivare%20i%20cookies](https://support.mozilla.org/it/kb/Attivare%20e%20disattivare%20i%20cookie)

  * Internet Explorer:[ http://windows.microsoft.com/it-it/windows7/block-enable-or-allow-cookiess](http://windows.microsoft.com/it-it/windows7/block-enable-or-allow-cookies)

  * Opera: <https://help.opera.com/en/latest/security-and-privacy/>

  * Safari: <https://www.apple.com/legal/privacy/it/cookies/>

If you use any other browser not listed above, check your browser settings for a tab that lets you manage cookies.

Between today’s many devices (from computers to smartphones to tablets), the user will have to check their web browser and settings on each device to ensure they are all aligned to reflect your own preferences as far as cookies go.

Please keep in mind that a full block of profiling cookies does not mean you are blocking ads from appearing on your web browser, you are simply ensuring that they are no longer personalized based on your browser activity.

If you want to learn more about cookies, check out [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/)

* * *

### Changes to this Privacy Statement and Cookie Policy

WebPromoter Snc has the discretion to update the privacy policy at any time to follow EU regulations. When we do, we will revise the updated date at the bottom of this page. We encourage users to check this page periodically for any changes to stay informed about how we are process the personal information we collect. You acknowledge and agree that it is your responsibility to review this privacy policy periodically and become aware of changes.

### Your acceptance of these terms

By using this website, you signify your acceptance of these policies. If you do not agree to these policies, please do not use our website. Your continued use of our site following the posting of changes to this policy will be deemed as acceptance of those changes.

### Contacting us

If you have any questions about this Privacy Statement, about our processing of your personal data, these terms or the use of cookies, please contact us via email at info@discovertuscany.com or webpromoter@registerpec.it.

**_Last update: May 24, 2018_**
